Finding Aid for Saline Woman’s Club (Mich.) Records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Saline Woman’s Club (Mich.) Records 1905-1987
Saline Woman’s Club (Mich.)
1.25 linear feet
852185 Bk.w 2
Administrative records, newspaper clippings, and photographs, 1905-1987, of the Saline Woman’s Club, founded in 1904. The organization’s initial literary focus later expanded to include welfare and civic improvements.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by the Saline (Mich.) Woman's Club through Mrs. F.N. Lockwood January 28, 1947, and Mrs. Edith Mueller, May 5, 1977 and September 26, 1988 (donor 2263 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The records are open to research.
Mrs. Jenny Brown and Mrs. Fannie Unterkircher co-founded the Saline Literary Club in 1904. As the Club's membership grew from its initial six female members, its literary endeavors expanded to include welfare and civic improvements. This development led to the Club's name being changed to the Saline Woman's Club in 1910. The Club joined the state federation in 1908 and the county federation in 1916.
Over the years, the many good deeds of the Club have included donations of food, clothes, and monetary funding to orphans, prisoners, the city of Saline, and victims of national disasters.
The records of the Saline Woman's Club include 1.25 linear feet of administrative records and clippings dating from 1905 to 1987. The collection is arranged alphabetically by topic, excepting a folder of organizational histories located at the front of the collection. Items within folders are arranged chronologically.
Of particular interest to the researcher will be the organizational histories, minutes, and presidents' reports which detail the Club's deeds and concerns.
Subjects:
Saline Woman's Club (Mich.).; Saline (Mich.).; Women--Michigan--Saline--Societies and clubs.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Costumes.; Saline (Mich.).; Saline Woman's Club (Mich.).; Women.; Women--Organizations.
Contributors:
Saline Woman's Club (Mich.).
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Topical Files
  - Organizational Histories (various dates) (Box 1)
  - Clippings, ca. 1910-1984 (Box 1)
  - Constitution, By-laws, Rules,1939-1982 (Box 1)
  - Minutes
    - June 1905-March 1909 (Box 1)
    - March 1909-May 1912 (Box 1)
    - October 1912-March 1916 (Box 1)
    - October 1930-May 1934 (Box 1)
    - September 1934-April 1938 (Box 1)
    - April 1938-September 1941 (Box 1)
    - October 1941-May 1945 (Box 1)
    - July 1945-May 1950 (Box 1)
    - June 1950-June 1955 (Box 1)
    - October 1955-May 1962 (Box 1)
    - October 1962-May 1968 (Box 1)
    - October 1968-May 1971 (Box 1)
    - October 1971-May 1977 (Box 1)
    - May 1977-September 1985 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, ca.1928-1984 (Box 2)
    - Presidents' Reports,1968-1986 (Box 2)
    - Yearbooks,1905-1906-1986-1987 (Box 2)
    - Photographs, 1960s-1980s (Box 2)